<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Shane Church</title>
  <subtitle>Software Developer</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://s-church.net/"/>
  <updated>2017-03-10T18:28:32.711Z</updated>
  <id>http://s-church.net/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Shane Church</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Stine Seed</title>
    <link href="http://s-church.net/blog/2017/02/07/stine-seed/"/>
    <id>http://s-church.net/blog/2017/02/07/stine-seed/</id>
    <published>2017-02-07T18:03:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-03-10T18:28:32.711Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday was my first day at my new job at <a href="https://www.stineseed.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">Stine Seed</a> in Dallas Center, Iowa. I’ll be doing Angular 2 development as well as full-stack .NET development in support of the research and breeding programs here. It’s a pretty small team here, consisting of just 5 full-time developers and one contractor. My first project is working on the user interface for the Breeder Mobile application that will be used on tablets to take field notes on different trials. I’m really excited to be part of the team here and I’m looking forward to learning more about the modern agriculture industry as I go.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Yesterday was my first day at my new job at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stineseed.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Stine Seed&lt;/a&gt; in Dallas 
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Developer" scheme="http://s-church.net/tags/developer/"/>
    
      <category term="Stine Seed" scheme="http://s-church.net/tags/stine-seed/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Fully Feedly</title>
    <link href="http://s-church.net/blog/2016/11/03/fully-feedly/"/>
    <id>http://s-church.net/blog/2016/11/03/fully-feedly/</id>
    <published>2016-11-03T15:28:15.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-03-10T18:21:58.168Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past few months, I’ve been contributing to an open source Chrome extension, <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/fullyfeedly/ikdncbjpcpkheefmnbicggciklkeebmp" target="_blank" rel="external">FullyFeedly</a> on <a href="https://github.com/Muffo/fullyfeedly" target="_blank" rel="external">GitHub</a>. It’s an extension I use every day to view the full content of my <a href="https://feedly.com" target="_blank" rel="external">Feedly</a> feeds inline instead of having to constantly open new tabs. </p>
<p>It’s been a pleasure to work with <a href="http://muffo.it/" target="_blank" rel="external">Andrea Grandi</a> to improve this great extension. It’s allowed me to keep my Chrome extension knowledge up to date and to contribute back to the community at the same time.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Over the past few months, I’ve been contributing to an open source Chrome extension, &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/f
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Development" scheme="http://s-church.net/tags/development/"/>
    
      <category term="Feedly" scheme="http://s-church.net/tags/feedly/"/>
    
      <category term="Chrome" scheme="http://s-church.net/tags/chrome/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Lightning Talks at Experiencing UX</title>
    <link href="http://s-church.net/blog/2016/04/21/lightning-talks-at-experiencing-ux/"/>
    <id>http://s-church.net/blog/2016/04/21/lightning-talks-at-experiencing-ux/</id>
    <published>2016-04-21T16:25:42.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-03-10T18:22:52.026Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night I had the pleasure of presenting a lightning talk at the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/experiencing-UX-DSM/" target="_blank" rel="external">Experiencing UX - Central Iowa meetup</a>. There were 4 presenters including myself. Lucas Freed (<a href="https://twitter.com/lucasfreed" target="_blank" rel="external">@lucasfreed</a>) presented on the Simplicity Project at Wells Fargo, Amanda Morrow (<a href="https://twitter.com/amandamorrow" target="_blank" rel="external">@amandamorrow</a>) shared her project of preserving and indexing her grandma’s notes in A World of Hurt, Matt Nowatzke (<a href="https://twitter.com/mattnowatzke" target="_blank" rel="external">@mattnowatzke</a>) presented on the 5 Second Test, and I presented on The Power of Leaving Things Out.</p>
<p><iframe src="//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/rdDvcJUsR05oZs" width="595" height="485" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;" allowfullscreen> </iframe> <div style="margin-bottom:5px"> <strong> <a href="//www.slideshare.net/churchs19/the-power-of-leaving-things-out" title="The Power of Leaving Things Out" target="_blank">The Power of Leaving Things Out</a> </strong> from <strong><a href="//www.slideshare.net/churchs19" target="_blank">Shane Church</a></strong> </div></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Be conscious about features you add. Don’t add a feature just because of one vocal customer.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The entire case study was built around my food journal app, <a href="/WhatIEat/">What I Eat</a>. I focused on the benefits of leaving features out and being very deliberate in which features you add. I think that I’ve only added 3 new features to What I Eat since I initially released it in 2013. </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Have a thick skin. I’ve had a number of 1 star ratings with the comment, ‘Does exactly what it says.’</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There’s clearly a market out there for a food journal app that doesn’t try to do too much.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Last night I had the pleasure of presenting a lightning talk at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/experiencing-UX-DSM/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; 
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="What I Eat" scheme="http://s-church.net/tags/what-i-eat/"/>
    
      <category term="UX" scheme="http://s-church.net/tags/ux/"/>
    
      <category term="Simplicity" scheme="http://s-church.net/tags/simplicity/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Creative Technologist</title>
    <link href="http://s-church.net/blog/2016/04/05/creative-technologist/"/>
    <id>http://s-church.net/blog/2016/04/05/creative-technologist/</id>
    <published>2016-04-05T18:00:03.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-02-20T15:33:42.497Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I started my new gig as a Creative Technologist at Nationwide Insurance. For those of you that don’t know, I was laid off by Two Rivers Marketing in February and have been looking for a new opportunity since then. As a Creative Technologist, my role is working with the User Experience (UX) team here at Nationwide to craft prototype and functional user interfaces for various applications here. My first project will be working on the conversion from Scottsdale Insurance to the Nationwide Excess &amp; Surplus branding.</p>
<p>I’m super excited for the new role and I think it will be a great fit to blend my technical expertise with the UX realm.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Yesterday I started my new gig as a Creative Technologist at Nationwide Insurance. For those of you that don’t know, I was laid off by Tw
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Des Moines" scheme="http://s-church.net/tags/des-moines/"/>
    
      <category term="UX" scheme="http://s-church.net/tags/ux/"/>
    
      <category term="Nationwide" scheme="http://s-church.net/tags/nationwide/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Dancing in Des Moines</title>
    <link href="http://s-church.net/blog/2016/03/20/dancing-in-des-moines/"/>
    <id>http://s-church.net/blog/2016/03/20/dancing-in-des-moines/</id>
    <published>2016-03-20T16:15:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-03-10T18:22:52.009Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, we were lucky that the Buffs got assigned to the NCAA Tournament site here in Des Moines! Given that I was still looking for a job, we didn’t think there was any way we’d be able to go to the games, so Ethan and I took the opportunity to go to the open practice on Wednesday at Wells Fargo Arena to check out the Buffs. While we were there, we lucked out and ran into my old friend from CU, former women’s basketball player, Kami Carmann. Kami’s working for CW 2 and Fox 31 in Denver as a sports reporter now and she was hunting for Buffs fans to interview, so she <a href="http://kdvr.com/2016/03/16/colorado-ready-to-take-on-uconn-as-ncaa-tournament-starts-thursday/" target="_blank" rel="external">interviewed us</a>! A little later, we were approached by a Des Moines Register reporter who wanted to take our picture for the Sunday Sketchbook they do. Sure enough, <a href="http://data.desmoinesregister.com/marturello/" target="_blank" rel="external">we were in the Sunday Register as well</a>!</p>
<p>Thursday morning, we decided to go to the Buffs Bash at the team hotel in West Des Moines for a free breakfast and to cheer on the team as they left for the game. Ethan and Colin loved watching Chip, the band, and the cheerleaders and Ethan can even sing along to the fight song. While we were there, the alumni association came around and asked if we had tickets to the game. We said no because at $100 each, the tickets they were selling were too rich for our blood, especially since we would have to buy a ticket for all four of us. We thought about it for a while and ten went back to chat with them some more. They offered to comp the two boys if we paid for Andrea and I. We said sure and took the chance, figuring the odds of ever getting to see the Buffs play in the Dance in our city again were slim to none.</p>
<p>So then we went down to the arena to get our tickets and watch the game. I still can’t believe we actually got to go! It was really a ton of fun. The boys were both enthralled with all of the action. CU dominated the first half, leading by 9 at the break, but went through one of our frustrating shooting droughts in the second half, eventually falling to UConn by a score of 74-67. After the Buffs game, our tickets also included the Kansas vs. Austin Peay game so we stayed for that one and had fun yelling “Let’s go Peay!” and rooting for the 16 seed. Kansas was pretty overwhelming though and ended up winning 105-79 in a game that was really never in question. </p>
<p>We had a great time even though it didn’t end like we had wanted. Thanks again to the <a href="http://www.colorado.edu/alumni/" target="_blank" rel="external">CU-Boulder Alumni Association</a> for making it possible for us to go. We’re Forever Buffs!</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;This week, we were lucky that the Buffs got assigned to the NCAA Tournament site here in Des Moines! Given that I was still looking for a
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="CU Buffs" scheme="http://s-church.net/tags/cu-buffs/"/>
    
      <category term="March Madness" scheme="http://s-church.net/tags/march-madness/"/>
    
      <category term="Des Moines" scheme="http://s-church.net/tags/des-moines/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
